{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Connelly","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel Weisz","Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including 'Requiem for a Dream' in 2000 and 'Hulk' in 2003?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George V","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth II","James III","Charles IV"],"question":"Who was the first Windsor monarch of the UK?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nine Inch Nails","incorrectAnswers":["The White Stripes","Creedence Clearwater Revival","Miley Cyrus"],"question":"Which artist first recorded 'Hurt', which was later covered by Johnny Cash?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Scotland","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Romania","Mexico"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink whisky?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Odin","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Freyr","Loki"],"question":"In Norse mythology, who is the ruler of all gods?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pacific","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantic","Indian","Antarctic"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Ocean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Diwali","incorrectAnswers":["Holi","Dusshera","Navaratri"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu festival of lights?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"David Ben-Gurion","incorrectAnswers":["Menachem Begin","Yitzhak Rabin","Ariel Sharon"],"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Israel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Justinian I","incorrectAnswers":["William the Conqueror","Cyrus the Great","George Washington"],"question":"Which influential historical person was Emperor of the Eastern Roman Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1976","incorrectAnswers":["1966","1971","1981"],"question":"Rocky was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dante Alighieri","incorrectAnswers":["Giovanni Boccaccio","Agatha Christie","Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Inferno'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Iced Tea ","incorrectAnswers":["Green Tea","Peppermint Tea","Afternoon Tea"],"question":"Which contribution to tea culture was introduced at the St. Louis world fair in 1904","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Green Bay Packers","incorrectAnswers":["Green Bay Raiders","Green Bay Canucks","Green Bay Mets"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Green Bay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George III","incorrectAnswers":["Henry I","Edward II","Anne"],"question":"Who was the monarch of The United Kingdom during the time period 1760-1820?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Burkina Faso","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Ivory Coast","São Tomé and Príncipe"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Togo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I feel the need - the need for speed!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Bond. James Bond.\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","\"Louis, I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Top Gun'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Cricket","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Henry Cooper associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ethiopia ","incorrectAnswers":["Syria","Egypt","Azerbaijan"],"question":"Which country was previously called Abyssinia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"study of the mouth and its diseases","incorrectAnswers":["music in society, usually non-western music","illness","embryos"],"question":"What is Stomatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Badminton","Surfing","Motor racing"],"question":"With which sport is Andy Murray associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'David Copperfield'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Goliath","incorrectAnswers":["Samson","Abraham","Moses"],"question":"In the biblical story, who did David defeat using a sling and some pebbles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Constantine","incorrectAnswers":["Justinian","Claudius","Julius"],"question":"Who Was The First Christian Emperor Of Rome?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Anthony Bourdain ","incorrectAnswers":["Michel Roux Jr","Gordon Ramsay","Heston Blumenthal"],"question":"Which Chef Wrote 'Kitchen Confidential'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Laika","incorrectAnswers":["Albert","Pirouette","Querida"],"question":"What was the name of the first animal (a dog) to orbit the earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"King of Macedonia and military leader.","incorrectAnswers":["Principal figure of Jainism.","Leader of the Russian Revolution and new Communist regime from 1917 to 1924.","French military and political leader."],"question":"Which of the following describes Alexander the Great?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"disease classification","incorrectAnswers":["the characteristics of the skull","the theological study of redemption","mental processes in living creatures"],"question":"What is Nosology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Upperclassman","incorrectAnswers":["Sophomore","Freshman","Senior"],"question":"In the USA, what term is used to refer to a student in the last 2 years of high school or college?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Carpenters","incorrectAnswers":["Builders","Plumbers","Electricians"],"question":"What do Karen, Richard and Joseph all have in common","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Palette","incorrectAnswers":["An eisel","A square","A pitcher"],"question":"What is the word given to a flat board used by a painter to mix and hold colors?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"600","incorrectAnswers":["Men","Doomed","Storm"],"question":"Complete the following line from 'The Charge of the Light Brigade' poem: 'All in the valley of Death rode the ___'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sachertorte","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"What is the name of a dessert which is a chocolate gateaux filled with apricot jam and topped with chocolate icing?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Focus","incorrectAnswers":["2CV","XK120","Corolla"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Ford?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["The Doors","The Rolling Stones","The Beatles"],"question":"What is the name of the band that wrote and performed the song \"Kashmir\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"one of two main branches of soil science","incorrectAnswers":["wood","Unidentified flying object phenomena","microorganisms"],"question":"What is Pedology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Adrian IV","incorrectAnswers":["Mark II","Alfred I","Clemence II"],"question":"Who Was The Only British Pope?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oldsmobile","incorrectAnswers":["Chevrolet","Ford","Nissan"],"question":"Which car model made the Cutlass Ciera?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Kiss Me, Kiss Me, Kiss Me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Great Escape","incorrectAnswers":["La Haine","Kill Bill: Vol. 1","There Will Be Blood"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Prisoners of war plan to escape from a German camp during World War II.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Switzerland","Luxembourg"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Andorra?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Caterpillar","incorrectAnswers":["A Codling","A Chick","A Spiderling"],"question":"A young butterfly is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Of all the gin joints in all the towns in all the world, she walks into mine.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"A boy's best friend is his mother.\"","\"Life is a banquet, and most poor suckers are starving to death!\"","\"What a dump.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Casablanca'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Linus Torvalds","incorrectAnswers":["Lin Wux","Lionel Uxworth","Linda Uxbridge"],"question":"Who is the Linux operating system named after?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Papaya","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Kiwi","Banana"],"question":"Which of these fruits is native to Central America?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Brazil","New Zealand"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Florence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Macho","A Bull","A Hob"],"question":"What is the word for a male pig?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Post-Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Crystal Cubism","Romanticism","Northern Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"Cafe Terrace at Night\" by ‎Vincent van Gogh is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","North America","Europe"],"question":"From which part of the world do cherries originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Finland","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Cuba","Canada"],"question":"Which country is also known as Suomi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bering Strait","incorrectAnswers":["Strait of Gibraltar","Bosporus Strait","Strait of Malacca"],"question":"Which strait lies between Alaska and Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"101 Dalmatians","incorrectAnswers":["Lady and the Tramp","The Fox and the Hound","The Aristocats"],"question":"In what Disney animated film is Cruella de Vil the villainess who kidnaps a group of animals?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Syria","incorrectAnswers":["Finland","Morocco","Somalia"],"question":"Damascus is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"England ","incorrectAnswers":["The Netherlands","Belgium","France"],"question":"Which Country Is The Source Of Stilton Cheese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["White","Blue","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Jamaica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Case-Book of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Toronto","incorrectAnswers":["New York","London","Minneapolis-St Paul"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Canada?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A Spare","incorrectAnswers":["A Strike","A Near","A Close"],"question":"In Bowling What Is The Term For Knocking Down All Ten Pins With 2 Consecutive Balls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Toto, I've a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\"","\"I’ve been a poor man and I’ve been a rich man. And I choose rich every f****** time!\"","\"I love the smell of napalm in the morning.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Wizard of Oz'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["India","Africa","China"],"question":"Where in the world are cranberries originally from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jupiter","incorrectAnswers":["Saturn","Uranus","Neptune"],"question":"What is the biggest planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1976","incorrectAnswers":["1966","1971","1981"],"question":"Taxi Driver was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Quark","incorrectAnswers":["Atom","Proton","Neutron"],"question":"What is the smallest particle known to exist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indlamu","incorrectAnswers":["Hula","Tango","Flamenco"],"question":"What is the traditional dance of the Zulu people of South Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"6","incorrectAnswers":["4","8","10"],"question":"How many pockets are on a regulation pool table?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rome","incorrectAnswers":["Athens","Jerusalem","Istanbul"],"question":"What ancient metropolis was built on seven hills, including Viminal and Aventine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cherry Blossom","incorrectAnswers":["Lily","Weeping Redbud","Dandelion"],"question":"What is often regarded as the national flower of Japan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Montreal Impact","incorrectAnswers":["Montreal Broncos","Montreal Mets","Montreal Bruins"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Montreal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zimbabwe","incorrectAnswers":["Zambia","Angola","Malawi"],"question":"Which of these countries borders South Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Unforgiven","incorrectAnswers":["The Crying Game","A Few Good Men","Howards End"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1992?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Celts","incorrectAnswers":["Huns","Gauls","Jutes"],"question":"Halloween originated from a festival celebrated by what ancient European people?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Blue","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Turkey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Oasis","Queen","The Clash"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Helter Skelter'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The 1963 assassination of President John F. Kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["The 1969 Manson Family murders","The 1974 abduction of heiress Patricia Hearst","The 1979 Jonestown mass suicide"],"question":"Which of the following famous criminal cases was solved by the use of ballistic evidence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bridgetown","incorrectAnswers":["Kingstown","Victoria","Dublin"],"question":"What is the capital city of Barbados?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mahershala Ali","incorrectAnswers":["Jeff Bridges","Lucas Hedges","Dev Patel"],"question":"Who won the 2016 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Juan in Moonlight?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Swimming","Sailing","Cycling"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Davis Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Buster Poindexter","incorrectAnswers":["Bow Wow Wow","Crash Test Dummies","Andrea True Connection"],"question":"'Hot, Hot, Hot' was a one hit wonder in 1987 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Lost World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"SMTP","incorrectAnswers":["FTP","HTTP","DNS"],"question":"Which protocol is used to send and receive emails?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tea ","incorrectAnswers":["Juice","Beer","Wine"],"question":"What Would You Be Drinking If You Were Given Earl Grey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tonga","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","Kyrgyzstan","Somalia"],"question":"Nuku'alofa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Drag","incorrectAnswers":["Thrust","Gravity","Lift"],"question":"What is the name of the force that resists the forward motion of a moving airplane?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Drone","A Tiercel","A Rooster"],"question":"A male sea lion is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Fergalicious\" by Fergie and will.i.am.","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young","\"All Star\" by Smash Mouth"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Listen up, y'all, 'cause this is it, the beat that I'm bangin' is de-li-cious.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Protection and mating displays","incorrectAnswers":["Digging and climbing","Attracting prey and communication","Receiving electromagnetic signals"],"question":"What was the purpose of the horns and plates that adorned some dinosaurs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Puzzles","incorrectAnswers":["Disease classification","Life in outer space","World War II"],"question":"What is enigmatology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Stranglers","incorrectAnswers":["Sex Pistols","Violent Femmes","T. Rex"],"question":"Who sang 'No More Heroes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hajj","incorrectAnswers":["Umrah","Haram","Ziyarat"],"question":"What is the name for the Islamic pilgrimage to Mecca?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Much Ado About Nothing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yemen","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Chile","Guatemala"],"question":"In which country would you find the Old Walled City of Shibam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Fish","incorrectAnswers":["Mountain range","Fighter jet","Hurricane"],"question":"Fandible, lateral line, and dorsal fin are parts of a what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The time are changing, and we change in them","incorrectAnswers":["What is said is done","The act done by me against my will is not my act","Mutiny against mutanous senators"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Tempora mutantur et nos mutamur in illis' translate into English?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"How to encode and decode secret messages","incorrectAnswers":["Animal diseases","Sacred texts","Burial grounds"],"question":"What is cryptology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Alexander Graham Bell","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Edison","Nikola Tesla","Benjamin Franklin"],"question":"Who created an audiometer to detect vestigial hearing in the deaf, among other inventions?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Uniform Resource Locator","incorrectAnswers":["Unique Resource Linker","Uniform Resource Linker","Universal Resource Locator"],"question":"In computer networking, what do the initials URL stand for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charlotte's Web","incorrectAnswers":["Animal Farm","Black Beauty","Watership Down"],"question":"Which book published in 1952 features an unusual friendship between a spider and a pig?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joseph Fiennes","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hiddleston","Benedict Cumberbatch","Hugh Grant"],"question":"Who played the title role in the movie Shakespeare In Love?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Bicycle Race'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue with a yellow cross extending to the edges.","incorrectAnswers":["Red with a white crescent moon and star.","Three equal horizontal bands of red blue and orange.","Red with a black two headed eagle in the center."],"question":"What does the flag of Sweden look like?","difficulty":"easy"},